<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 09:22:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Passing command line arguments to functions and methods with python-fire</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/454/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 09:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/454/</guid>
      <description>python-fire is a library to create CLI tools from Python objects.
$ pip install fire Just wrap with fire.Fire() to pass command line arguments to functions and methods.
$ cat main.py import fire class FizzBuzz: def fizzbuzz(self, num): ret = &amp;#34;&amp;#34; if num % 3 == 0: ret += &amp;#34;fizz&amp;#34; if num % 5 == 0: ret += &amp;#34;buzz&amp;#34; if len(ret) != 0: return ret return str(num) def fizzbuzzs(self, nums): return [self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning OpenAI&#39;s GPT with Japanese Prime Minister&#39;s speech in the Diet</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/452/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 23:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/452/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI provides APIs to create conversation and convert text to vector, and also fine-tune models with your own dataset, which enables us to improve the quality of the output or save the cost of few-shot learning. # !pip install openai import openai import numpy as np response = openai.ChatCompletion.create( model=&amp;#34;gpt-3.5-turbo&amp;#34;, messages=[{ &amp;#34;role&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;user&amp;#34;, # &amp;#34;system&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;user&amp;#34;, or &amp;#34;assistant&amp;#34; &amp;#34;content&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Is this a pen?&amp;#34; }], temperature=0.5, ) print(response.choices[0].message) &amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;#39; { &amp;#34;role&amp;#34;:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a cost-optimized real-time inference endpoint with SageMaker Inference Recommender</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/447/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 09:38:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/447/</guid>
      <description>SageMaker Inference Recommender is a feature to recommend endpoint&amp;rsquo;s instance types and settings. SageMakerで学習したPyTorchのモデルをElastic Inferenceを有効にしてデプロイする - sambaiz-net I</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering by k-means method with MLlib of Spark</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/446/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 17:08:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/446/</guid>
      <description>Spark has MLlib which is a library for machine learning. This article, try clustering using Kmeans.
K-means is a clustering method that randomly assigns each data to one of a pre-determined number of clusters first, computes the center of each cluster, and then updates the cluster assignment of each data to the cluster whose center is closest, which repeats until convergence. Kmeans is implemented in k-means++ that converges faster, and its default distance measure is euclidean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expresses a strength of the correlation between a categorical variable and a objective variable with the correlation ratio</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/441/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 23:55:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/441/</guid>
      <description>Pearson&amp;rsquo;s Product-Moment Correlation coefficient, calculated from the covariance \(\mathrm{Cov}(x,y) = E[(x - \bar{x})(y - \bar{y})]\) and the standard deviation \(\sigma_x = \sqrt{E[(x-\bar{x})^2]}\), is usually used for expressing the correlation. $$ \rho_{xy} = \frac{\mathrm{Cov}(x,y)}{\sigma_x \sigma_y} $$ However, since this coefficient expresses linear correlation between quantitative variables, it cannot be used for categorical variables, which are qualitative variables. The correlation between a qualitative and a quantitative variable can be expressed as the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python&#39;s built-in containers and collections.deque</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/436/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 16:32:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/436/</guid>
      <description>(C)Python has deque in the collections module in addition to build-in containers such as list, tuple, dict and set. $ python3 --version Python 3.10.7 list list is implemented with not linked-list but variable-length arrays. C++ STLのContainersとAlgorithms - sambaiz-net a = [&amp;#39;d&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;ae&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;ff&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;c&amp;#39;] print(a[2:-1])</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treat Spark struct as map to expand to multiple rows with explode</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/384/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 02:30:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/384/</guid>
      <description>When you read data without specifying schema in Spark, the schema is automatically determined from the input as follows. Why can Athena v2 fail to query map columns in parquet source tables - sambaiz-net # {&amp;#34;aaa&amp;#34;:123,&amp;#34;ccc&amp;#34;:[123],&amp;#34;eee&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;fff&amp;#34;:123},&amp;#34;hhh&amp;#34;:null} df = spark.read.json(&amp;#34;s3://hogefuga/testjson/&amp;#34;) df.printSchema() &amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;#39; root |-- aaa: long (nullable = true) |-- ccc: array (nullable = true) | |-- element: long (containsNull = true) |-- eee: struct (nullable = true) | |-- fff:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Job Bookmark of AWS Glue to process from the records following ones executed previously</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/333/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/333/</guid>
      <description>Job Bookmark of AWS Glue is a feature that saves what records are processed, and prevent it from being executed next time. Parquet and ORC, which were not supported before 1.0, are now supported. AWS GlueでCSVを加工しParquetに変換してパーティションを切りA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python with structural subtyping by Protocol</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/325/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 02:53:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/325/</guid>
      <description>In Python that has no interface syntax, it can assure that the function can be called by checking the function existance with hasattr(). However, this method needs to insert asserting each time and the error cannot be known until runtime. class ImplClass(): def foo(self): print(&amp;#34;ok&amp;#34;) class NoImplClass(): pass def call(d): assert hasattr(d, &amp;#39;foo&amp;#39;) d.foo() if __name__ == &amp;#34;__main__&amp;#34;: call(ImplClass()) # =&amp;gt; ok call(NoImplClass()) # =&amp;gt; AssertionError If you describe Type</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
