<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithm on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/algorithm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithm on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 23:55:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/algorithm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What do etcd, a distributed KVS with Raft, a consensus algorithm choose in the CAP/PACELC Theorem</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/473/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 23:55:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/473/</guid>
      <description>etcd is a distributed KVS that is also used in Kubernetes. Raspberry PiでおうちKubernetesクラスタを構築する - sambaiz-net Kubernetes docs say that etcd is a consistent and highly-available key value store, and so I wondered it compromises partition tolerance (P) in the CAP theorem. However, it feels difficult to</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read container/heap package in Go</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/456/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 21:48:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/456/</guid>
      <description>Go standard library has container/heap package which can be used to implement min/max heap and priority queue using this interface. It was implemented long time ago and there is a proposal to use Generics. C++ STLのContainersとAlgorithms - sambaiz-net type Interface interface { sort.Interface Push(x any) //</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement AVL tree, self-balancing binary search tree, in Go and confirm that the height is kept minimum</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/439/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:54:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/439/</guid>
      <description>AVL tree is one of the self-balancing binary search trees, which is a kind of binary search tree, and by keeping the height to a minimum, the computational complexity for operations can be reduced. Each time the tree is changed, if there is a height difference of 2 or more between left and right trees, they are rebalanced with rotation. Another self-balancing binary search tree example is a red-black tree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scheduler which allocates resources in Hadoop YARN, and Dominant Resource Fairness (DRF)</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/433/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 22:15:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/433/</guid>
      <description>YARN&amp;rsquo;s ResourceManager consists of ApplicationsManager, which receives applications from clients and launches ApplicationMaster, and Scheduler, which receives requests from ApplicationMaster and allocates resources.&#xA;How Hadoop YARN allocates resources to applications and check how much resources are allocated - sambaiz-net&#xA;Scheduler Scheduler has implementations such as CapacityScheduler, which aims to maximize the throughput in multi-tenant clusters, and FairScheduler, which allocates fair resources to all applications. You can choose to use which one with yarn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximum flow and minimum cut problem, Ford–Fulkerson algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/407/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 18:08:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/407/</guid>
      <description>Maximum flow problem Maximum flow promlem is a problem that maximizes the flow from the source to the sink in the network consisting of paths with capacity. It is necessary not to exceed the capacity and to equal input and output amount for each node. Besides, all of the data emitted from the source must be sent to the sink. Minimum cut problem Minimum cut problem is a problem that</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculate partial sum with Segment Tree or Bineary Indexed Tree (BIT)</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/406/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 19:18:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/406/</guid>
      <description>Segment Tree Segment Tree is a complete binary tree which can calculate partial sum at O(log n) by having the calculation results in each partials as node. In the following example, the calculated value is sum, but if it is the minimum value, Range Minimum Query (RMQ) can be solved and if it is the sorted list, merge sort is processed. When updating the value, recalculate in order from the</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check if there is a cycle in the undirected graph by Union-Find Tree</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/390/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 16:39:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/390/</guid>
      <description>Union-Find Tree Union-Find Tree is a data structure having some disjoint sets and can do &amp;ldquo;Union&amp;rdquo; which merges two sets, and &amp;ldquo;Find&amp;rdquo; which checks if two elements are in the same set with amortized O(α(n)) (α(n) is an inverse Ackermann function and smaller than log(n)). &amp;ldquo;Union&amp;rdquo; connects the tree with the smaller rank to under side so that merged tree</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implement Rabin–Karp algorithm in C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/387/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:38:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/387/</guid>
      <description>Rabin–Karp algorithm is a string-searching algorithm using rolling hash. Rolling hash can be made with O(1) by removing a first element from the previous hash and adding a next element to it. There are various hash functions which can do it, but for example, when simply summing up character codes, the hashes will collide just because the same character is contained,</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
