<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>presto on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/presto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in presto on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 01:49:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/presto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Performance comparison between Redshift Serverless and Athena using TPC-DS queries</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/397/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 01:49:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/397/</guid>
      <description>Redshift Serverless and other serverless aggregation services, run query with Glue Data Catalog - sambaiz-net
Compare the performance between Redshift Serverless and Athena by queries of TPC-DS, which is a database benchmark.
Generate data with TPC-DS Connector for Glue - sambaiz-net
First, executed the following query to the json and parquet data.
select /* TPC-DS query96.tpl 0.1 */ count(*) from store_sales ,household_demographics ,time_dim, store where ss_sold_time_sk = time_dim.t_time_sk and ss_hdemo_sk = household_demographics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redshift Serverless and other serverless aggregation services, run query with Glue Data Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/392/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 22:03:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/392/</guid>
      <description>Redshift Serverless Redshift Serverless is a new feature that can use Redshift, a petabyte-scale DWH without launching an instance, announced at this year&amp;rsquo;s re:Invent. It is available existing features such as Redshift Spectrum, refer to S3 directly, Federated Query to RDS, and Redshift ML. I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this update as it is costly to keep the instance running for occasional usage such as analytics. The cost is charged for at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Hive execution environment with Cloudera Docker Image and execute query to JSON log</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/128/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 09:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/128/</guid>
      <description>What is Hive Hive is a data warehouse software built on Hadoop, which can access data sources such as HDFS with HiveSQL, an extended SQL. Sending a query, the job runs on MapReduce, Spark or Tez. It has fault tolerance and is mainly used in batch processing. What is HDFS(Hadoop Distributed File System) - sambaiz-net Presto, which access data sources with SQL likewise, can execute the query faster than Hive</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
