<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presto on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/presto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presto on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 01:49:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/presto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compare Redshift Serverless and Athena performances by TPC-DS queries</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/397/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 01:49:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/397/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/392/&#34;&gt;Redshift Serverless and other serverless aggregation services, run query with Glue Data Catalog - sambaiz-net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compare the performance between Redshift Serverless (Preview) and Athena by queries of TPC-DS, which is a database benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(PS: 2022-07-13) Following values were calculated at the rate at the time of preview. When it became &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/jp/blogs/aws/amazon-redshift-serverless-now-generally-available-with-new-capabilities/&#34;&gt;GA&lt;/a&gt;, the rate dropped by about 30%.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/393/&#34;&gt;Generate data with TPC-DS Connector for Glue - sambaiz-net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, executed the following query to the json and parquet data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redshift Serverless and other serverless ETL services, run query with Glue Data Catalog</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/392/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 22:03:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/392/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;redshift-serverless&#34;&gt;Redshift Serverless&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/jp/redshift/redshift-serverless/&#34;&gt;Redshift Serverless&lt;/a&gt; is a new feature that can use Redshift, a petabyte-scale DWH without launching an instance, announced at this year&amp;rsquo;s re:Invent.&#xA;It is available existing features such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/dg/c-using-spectrum.html&#34;&gt;Redshift Spectrum&lt;/a&gt;, refer to S3 directly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/ja_jp/redshift/latest/dg/federated-overview.html&#34;&gt;Federated Query&lt;/a&gt; to RDS, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/dg/machine_learning.html&#34;&gt;Redshift ML&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this update as it is costly to keep the instance running for occasional usage such as analytics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/pricing&#34;&gt;cost&lt;/a&gt; is charged for at least 1 minute &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/mgmt/working-with-serverless.html#serverless-considerations&#34;&gt;RPU&lt;/a&gt; time and storage. RPU is a resource unit that contains 2vCPU and 16GiB memory and scales automatically.&#xA;The rate is &lt;strong&gt;$0.45/RPU hour&lt;/strong&gt; in Oregon, whereas Tokyo is set relatively high at &lt;strong&gt;$0.70/RPU hour&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;Since dc2.large (2vCPU, 15 GiB memory) instance is &lt;strong&gt;$0.314/hour&lt;/strong&gt; on-demand in Tokyo, if the resource usage is not over 40% on average due to like infrequent use or irregularity, it seems that the cost can be suppressed.&#xA;If RI is applied to the maximum, the rate becomes &lt;strong&gt;$0.110/hour&lt;/strong&gt; so the threshold drop to 15%, but there is also an operational advantage that you do not have to worry about the scale. In addition, there is no charge for the load amount of Redshift Spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Athena (Presto) and Glue (Spark) can return different values when running the same query</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/370/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 23:13:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/370/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS has multiple managed services that aggregate with SQL-like queries.&#xA;If queries are executed ad-hoc, Presto-based Athena, which can quickly and easily query to tables in Glue&amp;rsquo;s data catalog, is handy, while if heavy queries are executed in batch, Spark-based Glue, which can avoid resource and time limitation, can be better. Therefore, they can be used properly depending on the case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/392/&#34;&gt;Redshift Serverless and other serverless aggregation services, run query with Glue Data Catalog - sambaiz-net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launch Hive execution environment with Cloudera Docker Image and execute query to JSON log</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/128/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 09:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-hivehttpscwikiapacheorgconfluencedisplayhivehomehome-apachehive&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/Home#Home-ApacheHive&#34;&gt;What is Hive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hive is a data warehouse software built on Hadoop, which can access data sources such as HDFS with HiveSQL, an extended SQL.&#xA;Sending a query, the job runs on MapReduce, Spark or Tez.&#xA;It has fault tolerance and is mainly used in batch processing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/126/&#34;&gt;What is HDFS(Hadoop Distributed File System) - sambaiz-net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://prestodb.io/&#34;&gt;Presto&lt;/a&gt;, which access data sources with SQL likewise, can execute the query faster than Hive by parallelizing tasks and having intermediate data on memory, so it is suitable for an ad-hoc purpose.&#xA;On the other hand, if the intermediate data is large, it &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/jp/blogs/news/top-10-performance-tuning-tips-for-amazon-athena/&#34;&gt;takes a long time or can be failed&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Presto can refer to &lt;strong&gt;Hive metastore&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://prestodb.io/docs/current/connector/hive.html&#34;&gt;Hive Connector&lt;/a&gt;, so it can share the schema with Hive and query to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
