<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kubernetes on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kubernetes on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 20:59:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting security groups for EKS cluster&#39;s nodes created with CDK</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/459/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 20:59:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/459/</guid>
      <description>aws_eks.Cluster in CDK has a securityGroup field, but this is an SG associated with the ENI of the control plane, not the node. If it is not passed, it will be automatically created.
Then, where is the SG settings for EKS cluster&amp;rsquo;s nodes? It is in the node group. When you create an EKS cluster with CDK and DefaultCapacityType is NODEGROUP, which is the default, manged node group is created, which consists of defaultCapacity nodes and EKS performs drain etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Karpenter on an EKS cluster with CDK to auto-scale flexibility and quickly</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/455/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 20:35:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/455/</guid>
      <description>Karpenter is an OSS that scales a Kubernetes cluster developed by AWS. Compared to Cluster Autoscaler, it can perform fast and flexible provisioning not through Auto Scaling Group. It supports only EKS so far, but it seems to have possibility to support other cloud providers.
In this article, I install Karpenter on an EKS cluster with CDK, and confirm the cluster to be auto-scaled when the number of replicas is changed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launch an EKS cluster and register it to EMR on EKS with CDK to run Spark jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/434/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 14:53:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/434/</guid>
      <description>EMR on EKS is a feature to run Spark on EKS. While normal EMR also manages Hadoop clusters, EMR on EKS is only responsible for starting containers. Launch an EMR cluster with AWS CLI and run Spark applications - sambaiz-net By running on Kubernetes, you can use tools and functions for Kubernetes to manage and monitor, and utilize resources left over if you have an existing cluster. It also enables</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
