<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monitoring on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/monitoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monitoring on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 14:44:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate logs of spark running on an EMR cluster with Fluent Bit</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/416/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 14:44:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/416/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If Spark jobs run on Cluster mode, the logs are not outputted to step/ directory, so it is hard to check it on the console,&#xA;so try aggregating them to New Relic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/409/&#34;&gt;Launch an EMR cluster with AWS CLI and run Spark applications - sambaiz-net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/399/&#34;&gt;Monitor infrastructure and applications with New Relic - sambaiz-net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;option-1-sending-logs-with-self-installed-fluent-bit&#34;&gt;Option 1. Sending logs with self installed fluent bit&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.fluentbit.io/manual/about/fluentd-and-fluent-bit&#34;&gt;Fluent Bit&lt;/a&gt; that is memory saving fluentd, and send logs with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of Metrics and Events in New Relic and queries in NRQL</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/408/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 20:05:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/408/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Relic categorizes telemetry data into Metrics, Events, Logs and Traces, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.newrelic.com/docs/data-apis/understand-data/new-relic-data-types/&#34;&gt;MELT&lt;/a&gt;. Sent data can be queried in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.newrelic.com/docs/query-your-data/nrql-new-relic-query-language/get-started/introduction-nrql-new-relics-query-language/&#34;&gt;NRQL&lt;/a&gt;, standard SQL-like queries, shown on a dashboard, and targeted as alert conditions, but sometimes desired value can&amp;rsquo;t be obtained depending on the data type.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;metricshttpsdocsnewreliccomdocsdata-apisunderstand-datanew-relic-data-typesmetrics&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.newrelic.com/docs/data-apis/understand-data/new-relic-data-types/#metrics&#34;&gt;Metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Periodically aggregated and sent data. Having aggregated data, the transfer cost can be reduced and track the long-term trend, but there is a trade-off that the information required to aggregate later is lost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitor infrastructure and applications with New Relic</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/399/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 19:11:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/399/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newrelic.com/&#34;&gt;New Relic&lt;/a&gt; is a SaaS that monitors infrastructure and applications, and there is Datadog as a similar service.&#xA;It seems that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://newrelic.com/pricing&#34;&gt;pricing plans&lt;/a&gt; were &lt;a href=&#34;https://newrelic.com/jp/blog/nerdlog/new-relic-one-observability-made-simple&#34;&gt;changed&lt;/a&gt; drastically in 2020, and it charges according to the transfer volume and the number of admin users. Therefore compared to Datadog, which &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datadoghq.com/ja/pricing/&#34;&gt;charges&lt;/a&gt; for hosts and additional features, there is an advantage when managing a large number of instances with a small number of people.&#xA;And Datadog pricing plans are relatively complex and hard to estimate how much the bill will be in an environment where the number of instances increases and decreases frequently, while New Relic&amp;rsquo;s plans are easy.&#xA;Even if you try to new features, the unit price will not increase, so you can easily try it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
