<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hadoop on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/hadoop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hadoop on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 22:51:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/hadoop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make EMR clusters&#39; scale-in faster with Task nodes</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/445/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 22:51:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/445/</guid>
      <description>EMR cluster consists of a Master (primary) node and Core nodes and Task nodes.
How Hadoop YARN allocates resources to applications and check how much resources are allocated - sambaiz-net
Resources of both core nodes and task nodes are used to run tasks, but core nodes are HDFS&amp;rsquo;s DataNode while task nodes aren&amp;rsquo;t. Therefore, core nodes need to be decommissioned and then terminated to prevent data loss, but replication bandwidth is limited to prevent spikes, so it takes time to scale in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Scheduler which allocates resources in Hadoop YARN, and Dominant Resource Fairness (DRF)</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/433/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 22:15:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/433/</guid>
      <description>YARN&amp;rsquo;s ResourceManager consists of ApplicationsManager, which receives applications from clients and launches ApplicationMaster, and Scheduler, which receives requests from ApplicationMaster and allocates resources.
How Hadoop YARN allocates resources to applications and check how much resources are allocated - sambaiz-net
Scheduler Scheduler has implementations such as CapacityScheduler, which aims to maximize the throughput in multi-tenant clusters, and FairScheduler, which allocates fair resources to all applications. You can choose to use which one with yarn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Hadoop YARN allocates resources to applications and check how much resources are allocated</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/427/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 18:15:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/427/</guid>
      <description>YARN is a module that manages resources of a Hadoop cluster and schedules.
How Hadoop YARN allocates resources to applications Once ResourceManager (RM) receives an application from a client, it launches ApplicationMaster (AM) and passes information for executing the application. ApplicationMaster asks ResourceManager for allocating resources. After allocated, next it communicates with NodeManagers (NMs) running on each node, and then starts containers and runs the application.
The Scheduler which allocates resources in Hadoop YARN, and Dominant Resource Fairness (DRF) - sambaiz-net</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings for running Spark on EMR</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/414/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 19:53:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/414/</guid>
      <description>EMR and Glue are managed services that run Spark applications on AWS. Glue is easy to run ETL jobs with serverless, while EMR allows fine-tuning of resources and parameters. In other words, if the settings are not appropriate, the resources cannot be fully used, and tasks can fail due to OOM even if there is excess memory.
In the CLI, settings can be passed as json string or a file with &amp;ndash;configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch an EMR cluster with AWS CLI and run Spark applications</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/409/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:05:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/409/</guid>
      <description>Amazon EMR is the service that launches a cluster installed Spark, Hive, and Presto on EC2 or EKS. While Glue, the managed Spark service, can easily run Spark ETL jobs with serverless, EMR has the advantage of excellent cost performance by spot instances etc., and also fine-tuning is available, but now that EMR Serverless has been released, the difference has narrowed a little. Glue also has handy features such as</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Columnar format Parquet structure and read optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/386/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 20:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/386/</guid>
      <description>Parquet is a columnar format mainly used in the Hadoop ecosystem. Compared to row-based formats like CSV, unnecessary columns can be skipped. Besides, there is a mechanics to read only rows that are needed, so queries can be executed efficiently.
Format Rows are horizontally partitioned into some Row Groups, and the Column Chunks of each column are arranged in order. Column Chunks are divided into Pages, and compression and encoding are performed in that unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch Hive execution environment with Cloudera Docker Image and execute query to JSON log</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/128/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 09:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/128/</guid>
      <description>What is Hive Hive is a data warehouse software built on Hadoop, which can access data sources such as HDFS with HiveSQL, an extended SQL. Sending a query, the job runs on MapReduce, Spark or Tez. It has fault tolerance and is mainly used in batch processing. What is HDFS(Hadoop Distributed File System) - sambaiz-net Presto, which access data sources with SQL likewise, can execute the query faster than Hive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is HDFS(Hadoop Distributed File System)</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/126/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 22:52:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/126/</guid>
      <description>What is HDFS HDFS stands for Hadoop Distributed File System, one of the implementations of file systems for Hadoop, and other implementations include local files and S3. It distributes the disk I/O, which is a big problem when the data size is enormous and makes a block size, a unit for reading and writing, big to reduce the seek cost and improve the throughput.
You can see disk I/O can be a bottleneck from the data that while communication within the data center takes about 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
