<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machinelearning on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/machinelearning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machinelearning on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 23:22:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/machinelearning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning OpenAI&#39;s GPT with Japanese Prime Minister&#39;s speech in the Diet</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/452/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 23:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/452/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI provides APIs to create conversation and convert text to vector, and also fine-tune models with your own dataset, which enables us to improve the quality of the output or save the cost of few-shot learning. # !pip install openai import openai import numpy as np response = openai.ChatCompletion.create( model=&amp;#34;gpt-3.5-turbo&amp;#34;, messages=[{ &amp;#34;role&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;user&amp;#34;, # &amp;#34;system&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;user&amp;#34;, or &amp;#34;assistant&amp;#34; &amp;#34;content&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Is this a pen?&amp;#34; }], temperature=0.5, ) print(response.choices[0].message) &amp;#39;&amp;#39;&amp;#39; { &amp;#34;role&amp;#34;:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Japanese LLMs in TGI Container with SageMaker&#39;s HuggingFaceModel and generate texts</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/451/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 23:55:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/451/</guid>
      <description>Recently, some Japanese LLMs have been released in Hugging Face, such as OpenCALM-7B by CyberAgent and ELYZA-japanese-Llama-2-7b by ELYZA, spun-out from Matsuo Lab., University of Tokyo. SageMaker SDK has a HuggingFaceModel class, which can be used to deploy a model by specifying the model ID. Also, if you press the deploy button in Hugging Face, you can see the minimum code to run the model in SageMaker. get_huggingface_llm_image_uri() returns the</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check how job parameters of SageMaker Batch Transform work from called functions in entrypoint and its arguments</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/448/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 18:16:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/448/</guid>
      <description>SageMaker Batch Transform is a feature that runs a one-time batch inference job. It calls the entrypoint function of the Model as in the case of inference endpoints. I check how job parameters work from the function and its arguments. SageMakerで学習したPyTorchのモデルをElas</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a cost-optimized real-time inference endpoint with SageMaker Inference Recommender</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/447/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 09:38:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/447/</guid>
      <description>SageMaker Inference Recommender is a feature to recommend endpoint&amp;rsquo;s instance types and settings. SageMakerで学習したPyTorchのモデルをElastic Inferenceを有効にしてデプロイする - sambaiz-net I</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preprocess data with SageMaker Processing, train model with Training and record the parameters and accuracy with Experiments</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/442/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 19:20:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/442/</guid>
      <description>SageMaker Experiments is a feature to record parameters and metrics of Processing and Training jobs etc. In this article, I track from preprocessing to learning as a Run in Experiments and confirm that multiple results can be compared. The full code is on GitHub. SageMaker Experiments experiments.Run() creates an Experiment if it hasn&amp;rsquo;t existed yet and starts a Run. Previously, it was a separate library called sagemaker-experiments, but now it</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clustering by k-means method with MLlib of Spark</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/446/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 17:08:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/446/</guid>
      <description>Spark has MLlib which is a library for machine learning. This article, try clustering using Kmeans.
K-means is a clustering method that randomly assigns each data to one of a pre-determined number of clusters first, computes the center of each cluster, and then updates the cluster assignment of each data to the cluster whose center is closest, which repeats until convergence. Kmeans is implemented in k-means++ that converges faster, and its default distance measure is euclidean.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
