<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>database on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in database on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 01:49:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Performance comparison between Redshift Serverless and Athena using TPC-DS queries</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/397/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 01:49:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/397/</guid>
      <description>Redshift Serverless and other serverless aggregation services, run query with Glue Data Catalog - sambaiz-net
Compare the performance between Redshift Serverless and Athena by queries of TPC-DS, which is a database benchmark.
Generate data with TPC-DS Connector for Glue - sambaiz-net
First, execute the following query to the json and parquet data.
select /* TPC-DS query96.tpl 0.1 */ count(*) from store_sales ,household_demographics ,time_dim, store where ss_sold_time_sk = time_dim.t_time_sk and ss_hdemo_sk = household_demographics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate data with TPC-DS Connector for Glue</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/393/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 21:26:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/393/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I tried to generate 250GB of data with Athena&amp;rsquo;s TPC-DS Connector and output it to S3 but it timed out even if I increased the Lambda resource to the maximum, so I do it with Glue this time.
Generate data with TPC-DS Connector in Athena&amp;rsquo;s Federated Query - sambaiz-net
Subscribe and activate TPC-DS connector for Glue.
 Write a script like following. The scale is in GB, the same as Athena&amp;rsquo;s one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate data with TPC-DS Connector in Athena&#39;s Federated Query</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/391/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 23:55:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/391/</guid>
      <description>Athena&amp;rsquo;s Federated Query is a feature to execute queries on non-S3 data sources such as DynamoDB and RDS through Lambda function which is a data sources connector.
Implement Athena&amp;rsquo;s data source connectors and user defined functions (UDF)
 This article uses TPC-DS Connector in the AWS official repository. It generates the data of TPC-DS, which is a database benchmark in Decision Support.
Although it is in the official repository, it is a custom connector, so you need to build it yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
