<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prometheus on sambaiz-net</title>
    <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/prometheus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prometheus on sambaiz-net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>sambaiz-net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 02:22:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sambaiz.net/en/tags/prometheus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remote write aggregated data to New Relic using Prometheus recording rules for saving the amount of data</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/487/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 02:22:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/487/</guid>
      <description>Prometheus&amp;rsquo; recording rules is a feature that allows you to create new metrics from existing metrics in PromQL. This can save the amount of data sent to New Relic by sending aggregated data compared to sending raw data, but Prometheus in newrelic-prometheus-configurator included in newrelic-bundle is in Agent mode, so it doesn’t support Recording rules.&#xA;Install newrelic-bundle to EKS cluster with CDK and monitor it - sambaiz-net&#xA;So I install my own Prometheus using Helm and do remote write.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install newrelic-bundle to EKS cluster with CDK and monitor it</title>
      <link>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/466/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 21:07:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.sambaiz.net/en/article/466/</guid>
      <description>NewRelic Kubernetes Integration has various components, and nri-bundle Helm Chart bundles them. Proceeding with Guided install, the parameters to pass are generated, so I copied them to CDK. Looking at the chart, credentials can be passed as strings as it is or Secrets, so I imported them from SecretsManager with External Secrets. Install External Secrets Operator with CDK and make Secrets Manager data available as Kubernetes Secret - sambaiz-net const</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
